then you admit that Russia
то ты признаёшь что Россия в Курской
can’t do anything in the Kursk region, I
области ничего не может
think this has long been
сделать я это по-моему уже давно при
admitted, no, that is, you admit that
признал нет то есть ты признаёшь что
Russia is losing this
Россия проигрывает эту
war, Russia lost this war when it
войну Россия проиграла эту войну когда
started
начала
and they are losing
её и проигрывают
further, the only question is
дальше вопрос только в том
how much Putin will put in  storming of
сколько Путин положит своего при штурме
various Ukrainian fortified areas
разных украинских укрепрайонов
Hello, you are from Russia, I can see in your
Здравствуйте Вы откуда из России я вижу
face what city Novosibirsk is, I understand I am
по лицу город какой Новосибирск понял Я
from California Samen, you are studying somewhere,
из Калифорнии самен вы где-то учитесь
working, studying for someone.  advertiser,
работаете учусь на кого На рекламщика
how many
сколько
scholarships I got on the scarf And that they
стипендий я На платке понял А что на
didn’t apply for free, there weren’t
бесплатку не поступили там не было
free ones What kind of university is this
бесплат Что за университет такому
[music] I
[музыка]
understood in person So that means you work Well,
очно за оч понял Так значит работаешь Ну
yes, then Who do you
да то Кем
work in Yandex support
работаешь в поддержке Яндекса
I work how much
работаю сколько
salary Well about a month Well there it’s
зарплата Ну примерно в месяц Ну там
piecework from  40 somewhere from 40,000 rubles Well,
сдельно от 40 где-то от 40.000 руб Ну да
that’s it. Less than 400 dollars
это ж Меньше 400 долларов
is
получается как студенту
normal for a student. In California, homeless people
нормально в Калифорнии бездомные
receive three or four times more
получают в три или в четыре раза больше
payment Well, I understand, yes Russia America is
выплату Ну я понимаю да Россия Америка
cooler I’m just not in it at all No you’re
круче Я вообще просто не по Нет ты Ты
kidding me that how do you survive on
прикалываешься что как ты выживаешь на
[music]
[музыка]
dollars You’re trolling me nar
долларов Ты троллишь меня нар
no wait it’s a joke you’re studying, you
нет подожди прикол ты учишься ты же
dropped out
отчислился
I hear this
я слышу этого
dude I
чувака
understand Don’t pay
Понятно Не обращайте
attention What do you think  Why does Russia,
внимания Как ты считаешь Почему Россия
having such rich resources gold oil
имея такие богатые ресурсы золото нефть
gas diamonds, live so poorly
газ алмазы так бедно
due to corruption, probably And who is
живёт за счёт коррупции наверное А кто в
to blame for this Well, the fish rots from the head And more
этом виноват Ну рыба гниёт с головы А
specifically, the central person  Vladimir
конкретней центральное лицо Владимир
Vladimirovich n I thought you couldn’t
Владимирович н я думал ты так не сможешь
call him that. And who gave you this Putin,
назвать А кто поставил вам этого Путина
Americans, British,
американцы англичане
who came himself, well, well, he’s in
кто Сам пришёл ну как ну он же на
the elections, somehow people come and
выборах как-то его приходят люди что-то
vote for something. Well, in all elections except the very
голосуют Ну на всех выборах кроме самых
first, the result is, well, more precisely, a real
первых результат Ну точнее реальный
vote  citizens didn’t make much sense and
голос граждан не имел особого смысла а
you went to the last elections Yes and
ты ходил на выборы прошлые Да и что за
who did you vote for? For Davankov it’s cool because
кого голосовал за даванкова прикольно
he’s also like pro-government Vlad
так он же тоже типа про Влад провластный
Well, the least of all the candidates
Ну самый наименее из всех кандидатов
I didn’t understand Whose Crimea How are you  Do you
нане понял А чей Крым Как ты
think this is, well,
считаешь это ну как
how to
бы как бы правильно
put it correctly I think that at that moment there
выразиться Я думаю что в тот момент
really was the sympathy of many
действительно симпатии многих
people in this region. I will now
людей Сим Люде регионе я се сечас
explain my position. I will now explain
объясню свою позицию Я сейчас объясню
my position. The sympathy of many people.
свою позицию симпатии многих людей
Perhaps even the majority. But I
Возможно даже большинства Но это я не
cannot judge this. They were in the country of Russia.
могу судить были на стране России Так
that I think that specifically the issue with
что я думаю что конкретно вопрос с
Crimea needs to be resolved not just once again
Крымом надо решать не ещё раз ещё раз
no, look at the sympathies of people there,
нет смотри какие там симпатии людей
for example, the sympathies of people in Moscow may
например симпатии людей в Москве могут
be on the side of America Yes, but this does not
быть на стороне Америки Да но это не
mean that America should take
значит что Америка должна забирать себе
Moscow for itself  Yes, for example, Sympathy in Dagestan
Москву да например Симпатия в Дагестане
may be Turkey from an international point of view,
может Турции международной точки зрения
Crimea is part from your point of
Крым часть с твоей точки
view from mine I tried to explain to you but
зрения с моей Я пытался Вам объяснить но
you didn’t listen to me from your point of
вы меня не стали слушать с твоей точки
view You don’t consider Crimea part of
зрение Ты не считаешь Крым частью
Ukraine I think that the problem needs to be
Украины Я считаю что проблему Нужно
solved democratically what
решать демократическим какую
problem is what initially  there are people there I
проблему то что изначально там люди Я
say stop there is no problem The problem is not
говорю стоп нет проблема Проблема не
the people in Crimea the problem the Russian troops
люди в Крыму проблема российские войска
who came to Crimea is really
которые пришли в Крым это действительно
another problem and people’s sympathies are
другая проблема а симпатии людей вообще
not a
не
problem at all what
проблема а что
next Well what’s next Well I
дальше Ну что дальше-то Ну вот я же
say people’s sympathies are not a problem
говорю симпатии людей не проблема
Russian Intervention is a
Российская Интервенция - это
problem, the solution to the Crimea problem is very
проблема решение проблемы Крыма очень
simple, Russian troops are withdrawing from
простое российские войска выводятся из
Crimea and that’s it.
Крыма и всё
Well, they obviously won’t withdraw just like that, just like they didn’t
конечно также как просто так они не
withdraw from Kherson just like that. Yes, they were forced to
вывели же из Херсона Да их вынудили
withdraw from
вывести из
Kharkov, now the Russians are capable of forcing
Харьковской сечас способна вынудить уйти
the Russians to leave. Well, look, Ukraine is capable
российские Ну смотрите Украина способна
was able to force Russian troops to leave
была вынудить российские войска уйти из
part of the Kursk region,
части Курской области
well, if it can from Russian territory,
вполне если она может с россий террито
then why won’t it happen from Crimea
то почему с Крыма не будет
?
так А почему она до сих пор это не
why hasn’t she done this yet? Why hasn’t she done this yet? Because now she’s knocking out Russia in other directions, for example, Kherson, Kharkov, Kursk, Kiev, that is, look when it was. Well, look, in the second year they knocked out of Kyiv from Kherson with Kharkov in 1920, you were kicked out of the Kursk region, that’s 3 months ago. Well, you were kicked out of the Kursk region, of course, that’s a strong word. Well, that’s true, and everything in the Kursk region is part of the Kursk region under control  Ukraine and Russia
под контролем Украины и Россия ничего не
can’t do anything about this, nothing’s just stupid,
может с этим сделать ничего просто тупо
nothing, well, something will happen, I’m looking forward to your
ничего ну чтото будет я смотрю жду твою
reaction to what. Well, what do you say, yes,
реакцию на что Ну что ты скажешь да
indeed, Ukraine knocked Russia out of the
действительно Украина выбила Россию из
Kursk region. Russia can’t
Курской области Россия ничего не может
do anything, I admit, come on. Well, at the
сделать я признаю давай Ну в данный
moment there’s nothing in  at the moment no
момент нет что в данный момент нет не
Russia can’t do anything yes yes but this does
может ничего сделать Россия да да но это
not negate the fact that now
не отменяет того факта что сейчас
Ukraine is retreating in almost all directions.
Украина практически на всех направлениях
In which all directions in the Donbass. In
отступает На каких всех на Донбассе На
which all directions is retreating?
каких всех направлениях на отступает
Lord good look, Ukraine  The Ukrainian
Господи доба смотри Укра украинская
army occupied more territory in 2 weeks of the Kursk operation
армия так за 2 недели Курской операции
than Russia did in the
заняла территории больше чем Россия за
entire 2024. Well, this is not true, this is
весь 2024 год Ну вот это неправда это
true, but look at the area and the
правда да посмотри по площади и по
number of settlements
количеству населённых пунктов
Yes, Ukraine is currently retreating in the
Да Украина в данный момент отступает на
Donbass in the area of ​​the Oskol River, these are two Well,
донбасе в районе реки Оскол это два Ну
one of the main ones  directions to
одни из основных направлений
Vrana in the area of ​​the Askol River you were also knocked out
вране в районе реки аскол вас ещё выбили
in this
в этом
year 2022 to Kharkov you ran away for
2022 году на Харьков вы убежали за
Askol
аскол
this is understandable but in the area of ​​the Askol River they are
это понятно но в районе реки аскол всё
still leading  tell me, come on,
ещё ведут скажи скажи вот давай так
just tell me how many
просто скажи за 2024 год на сколько
kilometers the Russian army has advanced
километров продвинулась Российская армия
in the Donbass in 2024. Well, it’s just not.
на Донбассе Ну вот вот просто нет Ты
Look, if you’re not following, you just
смотри если ты не следишь ты только что
voiced Ukra with your mouth. I follow the
своим ртом озвучил Укра слежу за
news a lot to know how many
новостями сильно чтобы знать на сколько
kilometers they’re from. And where are you from?  you know
километров они откуда А откуда ты знаешь
that Ukraine is retreating in all
что Украина отступает на всех
directions I’m not saying that Ukraine is
направлениях Я не говорю что Украина
retreating you said you said in your own
отступает ты сказал ты сказал своими
words with your
словами своим
mouth I said that it is retreating
ртом я сказал что она отступает
in almost all main
практически на всех основных
directions And what are Which  name
направлениях А что такое Какие назови
what are the main directions in the Donbass
какие основные направления на Донбассе
What are the main directions in the Donbass
Какие основные направления на Донбассе
open the map No, wait, you’re
карту открыть Не ну подожди ты ж типа
not like you’re watching the news But it
это не смотришь новости Но у тебя
starts in your head It’s turning on
начинается в голове Это включаться
Compare the area that Russia Russia
Сравни площадь которую России Россия
was able to capture in 2024 in the Donbass And
смогла захватить в 2024 на Донбассе Да и
the area of ​​the Kursk region that Ukraine
площадь Курской области которую Украина
captured  liberated more precisely in
захватила в освободила точнее в 2024
2024 in the Kursk region, more
году в Курской области больше
clearly Ukraine is taking from Russia more
явно Украина забирает у России больше
than Russia and
чем Россия и
Ukraine, everything that Russia captured quickly,
Украины всё что Россия захватила быстро
this was in 22 when Ukraine
это было в 22 году когда Украина
wanted  In order to resolve everything peacefully, and Russia
хотела Чтобы вс мирно порешать а Россия
violated all the agreements and attacked
нарушила все договорённости и напала
at night, so yes specifically under the hour
ночью так да конкретно под часовым
yar that by the hour How many kilometers
яром что по часам Сколько километров
Look at this from the know How many kilometers
Смотри вот это от зна Сколько километров
Well, just like that, look look look
Ну так вот так посмотри посмотри смотри
Look at the map the change in the front line
Посмотри на карту изменение линии фронта
for a year yes there is animated Russia has
заче год да там анимировано Россия
advanced  in general, there is something like 10 km
продвинулась на вообще там что-то 10 км
in the sum. I don’t argue that the progress is
в суме Я не спорю что продвижение
small, but Well, I’m saying if
маленькое но Ну так я же говорю если
Ukraine, look if Ukraine is completely for
Украина смотри если Украина совсем за
the whole of Russia  for the entire twenty-four
весь Россия за весь двадцать четвёртый
year there, in some
год там на километров 10 в некоторых
places only the maximum has advanced by 10 kilometers. Yes, and
местах только максимум продвинулась Да а
Ukraine has advanced by 40-50, but in the Kursk
Украина на 40-50 в это в Курской
region the area is definitely larger,
области однозначно площадь больше
the number of settlements is an
количество населённых пунктов больше на
order of magnitude larger, let’s say
порядок допустим
then you admit that Russia is in the Kursk
то ты признаёшь что Россия в Курской
region and cannot
области и ничего не может
do anything  I, in my opinion, have already admitted this a long time ago,
сделать я это по-моему уже давно признал
no, that is, you admit that Russia is
нет то есть ты признаёшь что Россия
losing
проигрывает эту
this war. Russia lost this war when
войну Россия проиграла эту войну кода
it started and they continue to lose, the
её и проигрывают
only question is
дальше вопрос только в том
how much Putin will put in  storming of
сколько Путин положит своего при штурме
various Ukrainian fortified areas
разных украинских укрепрайонов
that once again the only question is
что ещ раз вопрос лишь только в том
how many Russians Putin will put down during the
сколько Путин положит российского при
storming of Ukrainian fortified areas until he is
штурме украинских укрепрайонов пока его
overthrown, this is a question for me, I don’t
свергнут это вопрос ко мне я не
understand, well,
понимаю ну
first of all, that’s how it applies, but why should I
во-первых так и относится но зачем мне
treat them like that, look people who are running
относиться смотрите люди которые бегут
people  to a foreign country and are driven in droves to do
людей в чужую страну и гонят толпами на
this on Ukrainian prions Yes,
это на укре прионы Да
what do they
они причём
have to do with it? Instead of
получается Они вместо того чтобы
rebelling against their own, these
восстать против своих вот этих
Commissars who are driving to Ukraine
Комиссаров которые гонят в Украину
against Putin they go and
против Путина они идут и
die and the
умирают а
alternative I’m not talking about I’m
альтернатива Я же не говорю про Я же
saying why is this, you see, he has no
говорю почему это вот видишь у него нет
alternative when a sheep is taken to a
альтернативы когда барана ведут на
meat processing plant Yes, he has no
мясокомбинат Да у него нет
alternative, he is for meat Let’s
альтернативы он его на мясо Давайте
imagine the
представим
situation Here you are a soldier at the front Yes, no
ситуацию Вот вы солдат на фронте Да нет
again  look we are concretely no look
ещё раз смотри мы конкретно нет смотри
again we are specifically saying no look
ещё раз мы конкретно говорим нет смотри
No no no no no again you are no
Нет нет нет нет нет ещё раз ты никаких
abstract situations the concrete situation of
абстрактных ситуаций конкретная ситуация
Russian citizens yes some Dictator
граждан России да какой-то Диктатор
is driving them to die in a foreign country yes they have
гонит умирать в чужую страну да у них
no they have no options I agree
нету у них нету вариантов Я согласен
no one can escape abroad
никто не может не убежать за границу из
none of them are shorter than their Commissioner
них ни короче своего Комиссара ничего
nothing they can’t they Yes them How they lead
вот они не могут они Да их Как ведут они
how they do it all yes I’m not saying
как это делают всё да я же не говорю
why they don’t have other options there
почему у них нету там других вариантов
that’s all  so yes yes They are not to blame
что всё вот так есть да Они не виноваты
that they are
что они
true Well Well ok Yes I understand that is they are
правда Ну Ну хорошо Да понял то есть их
just being driven like they are We are not saying
просто гонят как они Мы же не говорим
that they are to blame well they are driven like
что они виноваты ну погнали он как
everyone else you know someone who
всё у тебя из знакомых есть кто-то кто
fought or is fighting
воевал или воюет
Well, after a couple of hands so  say  there are already dead
Ну через пару рук так сказать погибшие
among the acquaintances no yes And there are wounded
есть из знакомых нет да А раненые
wounded yes
раненые есть да что
nothing was torn off And what
оторвало ничего не оторвало А что
concussion can be
контузии может быть
such as you see How this
такое как ты видишь Чем закончится эта
war will end I cannot
война не могу
predict Why many people in the
прогнозировать Почему много людей в
Russian Federation support this
Российской Федерации поддерживает эту
war I would not say that many people in  The
войну я бы не сказал что много людей в
Russian Federation supports this
Российской Федерации поддерживают эту
war, well, people are signing a contract. They are going to get
войну ну люди на контракт Идут
money from people in
подписывают Идут за бабки людей в
Ukraine.
Украине
Well,
Ну
maybe from other places. It looks like that,
может из других мест Это так и выглядит
but people are coming mainly from poor
но идут люди в основном из бедных
regions whose alternative is to
регионов которых альтернатива - это
continue living under
продолжать жить под
collectors make money from
коллекторами зарабатывать на
all sorts of minute
всяких минутных
jobs. That is, it turns out that people
работах То есть получается люди
deliberately, instead of when you
сознательно вместо того когда ты
said we were talking about meat, they have no
говорили мы говорили про мясо у них нет
choice. Yes, they are forced. And here it is already a
выбора Да их заставляют А тут это уже
conscious choice, but
сознательный выбор да
at a poor job or to go to
на бедной работе или пойти за деньги
fight in Ukraine for money, this is already a conscious
воевать в Украину это уже сознательный
choice,
выбор
the truth here  you can’t tell anymore, they are
правда тут ты уже не скажешь вот их там
forced there, they have no choice, it’s true that
заставляют у них нет выбора правда
someone is forced, someone actually
кого-то заставляют кто-то действительно
signs a contract because they
подписывает контракт из-за того
simply cannot live in such
что не может просто больше жить в такой
poverty anymore, sous the state, using
нищете су государство как
such financial methods, one might say
такими финансовыми можно сказать
forces some people to
методами принуждает людей некоторых
serve Yes Absolutely true but look
служить Да Абсолютно верно но вот смотри
these people if a person lives poorly and
Эти люди если человек живёт бедно и
because of this he robs someone or
из-за этого берёт кого-то грабит или
kills someone because it’s hard for him to
кого-то убивает потому что ему тяжело
live in poverty Yes, he’s doing this since it’s a
жить бедно Да он занимается раз так это
crime he specifically turns out like
Преступление это он конкретно получается
this here  the same thing I'm not saying that the fact
так тут то же самое Я не говорю что то
that they go for money is good It's
что они идут за деньги это хорошо Это
bad no So I'm saying that these people
плохо нет Так я говорю то есть Эти люди
They go deliberately, they have a life and so
Они идут сознательно у них жизнь и так
on they go deliberately to make
дальше они идут сознательно срубить
money in order to destroy some
бабла на том чтобы уничтожить каких-то
people  in a foreign
людей в чужой
country and there are a lot of them,
стране и таких много ж
but for some reason I don’t see the
правда я я почему-то не вижу
mothers of these people Yes, the wives there are happy
чтобы мамы этих людей Да там сст жёны
with everything, everyone is
возб все всех все
happy with everything Well, there are relatives of the
устраивает Ну существуют родственники
mobilized, too, they are something there a couple of
мобилизованных тоже они что-то там пару
times 10 people held a rally and that’s it Well, not
раз 10 человек митинговала и всё Ну не
10 people and  more than a couple of times they still
10 человек и не пару раз всё ещё они
continue actions
продолжают акции
where in Moscow, for example,
где в Москве например
when I don’t remember every day of the
когда я не помню каждый какой-то день
week they come out, how many of them come out
недели они выходят сколько их выходит
there, that’s interesting, I’m currently naive
там вот интересно я сейчас нагу
to google Well, tell me what the name of the action is
на гуглить Ну скажи как называется акция
Where When you can here  find it at home too And
Где Когда можешь вот у себя найти тоже И
tell me I Well, let’s say I’m interested in
мне сказать я Ну допустим мне интересно
how many of them there are 10 people
сколько их выходит 10 человек
[laughter]
[смех]
[music]
[музыка]
here’s an action of about 2 participants in Moscow
вот акция около 2 участников в Москве
200 participants are from all over Russia They and
200 участников это со всей России Они
what’s the name of the action Let me
да как акция называется Давай я сейчас
look at the news now How  it's called I've
посмотрю новость Как называется я закрыл
already closed it like that
уже так
Open Yes, I'm aware of
Открой Да я в курсе в
it Well, I don't see the name here Well, you can
курсе Ну название я тут не вижу Ну можно
just move the way
просто акция движения путь
home for what date
домой за какое число
there I see in February there was something there in
там Я вижу в феврале что-то там было в
February Yes, well, you  you say it
феврале было Да вот ну ты же говоришь
comes out Take for November October
выходит Вот возьми за ноябрь октябрь
there is something now just a second
есть что-то сейчас секундочку
[laughter]
[смех]
here in February I look Yes they
вот в феврале смотрю Дато цветы
laid flowers there And then there are not 200 of them there
возложили там И то их там не 200 человек
Senya unfortunately didn’t manage to put flowers on the campaign, no
Сеня на акци ложения цветов к сожалению
there are 200 people there, we
удалось нету там 200 человек там сотки
don’t even have hundreds,
даже нет
apparently they stopped  because of the
видимо свернули из-за
arrests, on September 21 I watched the action of Jean
арестов вот 21 сентября смотрю акция Жан
Mobil called in Moscow, there are 10 of them here
мобили званных в Москве вот их тут 10
in the photo with posters
человек на фотографии с плакатами
for the protest, 10 people all come out  It’s
на протест 10 человек выходит все РОСИ
very convenient for ROSI to sit in the USA and
очень удобно сидеть в США и что-то
talk something about the fact that people don’t go out,
рассуждать про то что люди не выходят
of course yes yes Well, it’s more convenient for me and the USA. I’m
конечно да да Ну мне и США удобнее Я же
talking to you. You live in Russia, you’re
и общаюсь с вами Вы живёте в России вы
building your own state, you’re being driven to
строите свою государство вас гонят на
slaughter in a foreign country. When we have the USA in
убой чужую страну Когда у нас США во
She fought in Vietnam We, too, had people
Вьетнаме воевала У нас тоже люди
fighting with the
выходили с
legal US would have been the aggressor no the US did
законным США бы агрессором нет США на
not attack Vietnam no the US was in
Вьетнам не нападала нет США как раз во
Vietnam Yes there was an official
Вьетнаме Да было официальное
government which the US helped and there
правительство которому помогало США и
were militants whom he helped  The Soviet
были боевики которым помогал Советский
Union, which fought against this
Союз которая воевала против это
legitimate friendship of Vietnam, and
законного приятельство Вьетнама да
look, it was no longer the
посмотри боевикам помогал больше не
Soviet Union that helped the militants, but North Vietnam. The
Советский Союз а Северный Вьетнам
Soviet this so-called
Советский вот этот так называемый
North Vietnam. It was like the DPR, it’s that the
Северный Вьетнам Это же было как ДНР это
Soviet made a fake
то что Советский сделал фейковую там
Republic there like that’s all. Well, if you
такую Республику типа вот и всё Ну Если
think like that then  and South Vietnam
рассуждать так то и Южный Вьетнам в
as a whole was a fake Republic there is no
целом был фейковой Республики нет
Vietnam Look Vietnam is what you
Вьетнам Вот смотри Вьетнам то что вы ты
call South Vietnam Yes it was the
называешь Южный Вьетнам Да это был
official authorities were
официальные власти были
official there And before that they were  any
там официальные А до этого были какие-то
authorities at all in Vietnam besides the French
вообще власти во Вьетнаме кроме франци
of course there were don’t look again Vietnam
конечно были не смотри ещё раз Вьетнам
in Vietnam there were official authorities Yes the official
во Вьетнаме были официальные власти Да
authorities were helped by the USA that is the
официальным властям помогало США то есть
USA helped at the request of the official
США помогала на запрос официальных
authorities according to international according to
властей согласно международному согласно
international law wait don’t
международному праву подожди не
interrupt me don’t interrupt the Soviet
перебивай меня не перебивай Советский
Union
Союз
Yes supported the militants  not
Да поддерживал боевиков никем не
recognized by anyone, not having official power,
признанных не имеющих официальной власти
yes, that is, in
да то есть в
violation of the UN statute Yes, the Soviet Union
нарушении статута ООН Да Советский Союз
used its aviation there Yes, against the
использовал там авиацию свою Да против
official authorities of Vietnam, that’s
официальных властей Вьетнама вот
Absolutely true, that’s why the United States was not in
Абсолютно верно поэтому США не были во
Vietnam  aggressors Yes, the United States helped a
Вьетнаме агрессорами Да США помогали
friendly country But besides this, there
дружественной стране Но кроме этого в
were people in the United States who believed that there was no
США были люди которые считали что не
need to fight there in Vietnam because
нужно там воевать во Вьетнаме потому что
there were a lot of deaths there and there were various
это много там смертей и были разные
protests, yes But in Russia
акции протеста да А вот в России
no, maybe because in a Democratic
нет может потому что в Демократической
country they don’t give sentences for that  what are you
стране не дают сроки за то что ты
speaking against, I’m not arguing, I’m not
выступаешь против я же не спорю я же не
SPO and who is to blame that your country is
СПО а кто виноват что у вас страна
undemocratic, a
недемократическая
person who seized power
человек который захватил власть
probably That is, it turns out that one
наверное То есть получается один
person is keeping 140 million people in fear,
человек держит в страхе 140 млн людей
yes Well, he has it I’m just wondering how
да Ну у него Мне просто интересно как
atomization  apathy Yes, I’m just
атомизации апатии Да мне просто
wondering how it works. This
интересно как это работает у этого
person has some kind of Magic ball of
человека есть какой-то Магический шар
power and he kind of holds these people.
власти и он типа держит этих людей
That is, it turns out that Millions of people
То есть получается что Миллионы людей
work for this person.
работают на этого человека
True. Well, it turns out like this, that
Правда Ну получается получается так то
is, the Russian people in their mass
есть российский народ он в своей массе
support this
поддерживает этого
dictator  well, silent support Yes, not
диктатора ну молчаливой поддержкой Да не
only not only not only silent but with
не только не не только молчаливый а
active support his active
активной поддержкой его активная
support is a tiny percentage like
поддержка - это мизерный процент как
sri everyone who works for the authorities this is
сри все все кто работают на власти это
all active
всё активная
support po amounts to Well, in general, such
поддержка ро составляет Ну в целом такие
middle-aged women and that in itself
женщины среднего возраста и это само по
yourself a stratum such Amirova very once again
себе страта такая Амирова ная очень ещё
you said the majority of the population of
раз ты сказал большинство населения
Russia is middle-aged women
России - это женщины среднего возраста
predominant so because of this what
преобладающая так сза это сколько
percentage Now
процентов Сейчас
I’ll find it very interesting the phrase
найду аж интересно стала фраза
according to the population census of the tenth
по данным переписи населения десятого
year in Russia 54% of
года в России 54%
women Well women And you say
женщин Ну женщин А ты говоришь женщин
middle-aged women predominate  54% here are
среднего возраста преобладающих 54% вот
half the women half the
половина женщин половина
men
мужчин
Ay And what about the
Ай А что там с
preo of middle-
прео женщин среднего
aged women middle-aged 62 of the population
возраста среднего возраста 62 населения
So these are not women, but simply middle-
Так это не женщин а просто среднего
aged Well, you can’t count in your head
возраста Ну посчитать в голове нельзя
what you said, the
что ты ты сказал
predominant number of the population of
преобладающее количество населения
Russia are middle-aged women
России - это женщины среднего возраста
I say Where did you get what
говорю Откуда ты такой взял сколько их
percentage of them? Well, yes, most of the women and the
процентов Ну да большинство женщин и
majority of the
большинство
middle age And how many middle-
среднего А сколько женщин среднего
aged women are now
возраста сейчас
[music]
[музыка]
wait a second it will be 30-something percent
секундочку будет 30 с чем-то процентов
now for you Yes, what 30-something percent is it
сейчас у тебя Да какие 30 с чем-то проце
if you have a middle age of 60?
если у тебя среднего возраста 60 с
something and 54% of them will be women And
чем-то а женщин из них 54% будет И
now you will have uh around 35% 35-37
сейчас у тебя будет э в районе 35% 35-37
about convenient from 35 to 38% there will be
про удобный от 35 до 38% будет
middle-
женщин среднего
aged women there is some kind of
возраста вот ф какая-то есть
[music]
[музыка]
that women, that women of this middle
что женщины что женщины этого среднего
age, that they No, this is generally a stratum
возраста что они Нет это в целом страта
more than Amirova, but in general,
более Амирова но и в целом общество
Russian society is very atomistic
России очень атоми
Zro So
Зро Так что
their overall social life is connected with the
их в целом социальная жизнь связаная с
state, it is expressed in tacit
государством она выражается в молчаливой
support, you don’t touch us and everything is normal
поддержки вы нас не трогаете и всё норм
in such a society  in general, not inclined to
такое общество в целом не склонно к
protests, the question is interesting, but what if tomorrow
протестам вопрос интересно а если завтра
the Dictator passes a law that every man
Диктатор примет закон что каждый мужчина
should be
должен быть
you with
вы
the rods, show up completely at the beating point You
прутьями яви совсем на изби пункт Ты
will go
пойдёшь
no, that is, you will go against the law
нет то есть ты будешь идти против закона
I am not going to obey the stupid and
Я не собираюсь подчиняться глупым и
illegal laws are good And if you are
незаконным законам хорошо А если тебя
taken into the army, you will go
возьмут в армию пойдёшь
[music]
[музыка]
they resist doing conscript service
сопротивляются служить срочную службу
people in Ukraine so in conscript service so
людей в Украину так на срочной служ так
urgently they quit fighting This is the second
срочни бросают воевать Уже второй
person who says this so there are
человек который это говорит так есть
tire conscripts only at the beginning of
шинные срочники были только в начале
the war then now look
войны потом вот сейчас посмотри вот
now
сейчас
they google it  now the region is only near Kursk,
загугли сейчас край только под Курском
if that makes any difference, the war is a war near
если та какая разница война война под
Kursk, not near
Курском не под
Kursk, that is, you see, when they pass
Курском то есть Видишь Когда примут
the law so that you will be treated with rods
закон чтоб розгами ты будешь неже про бу
no less about the boos.  M, let’s have a protest Let’s not have 20
Не М давайте будет протест Давайте не 20
blows
ударов
Let’s do it because 20 is already
Давайте потому что 20 это уже
too much Well, that is, how do your Russian
слишком Ну то есть как ваш российский
people see a way out of this
народ видит Выход из этой
situation? I don’t understand the meta, hear,
ситуации Я не понимаю мете услышать
communicate, I’m interested as a person
общаюсь мне интересно как человеку
who once lived in Russia, how
который когда-то жил в России как сейчас
people live in
люди живут в
Russia now  they live an ordinary
России живут обычную
life, why do you go out to chat roulette
жизнь а зачем ты выходишь в чат рулетку
with Ukrainians
с украинцами
to communicate? You came across me by chance. Well, before
общаться Вы мне случайно попались Ну до
that, you also came across Ukrainians by chance, but
этого тебе тоже случайно попадались
why did you come across them? Well, a couple of times it was probably yes. How are you dealing with them?  communicated Well, there were
А чем ты с ними общался Ну бывали
normal people We just talked and everyone
нормальные люди Просто пообщались и всё
was like you, I mean, there were
бывали вот типа вас в смысле бывали
normal people and there were people like me, that
нормальные люди а бывали типа меня то
is, a person who does not
есть человек который не
support your Russian position, is he
поддерживает вашу российскую позицию он
crazy? God, I meant that there were people with whom you just can have a nice
бывали люди с которым просто можно мило
conversation We too  we communicate nicely we
Пообщаться мы тоже мило общаемся
don’t call names sulfur we communicate
помы не обзываем льно серно ми общаемся
I smile I ask M provocative Question
я улыбаюсь задаю М провокационные Вопрос
rather some kind of discussion in general And what
скорее какая-то дискуссия обще А что
discussion can’t be nice
дискуссия не может быть милым
communication discussion is  a clash of
общение дискуссия - это столкновение
some positions And nice communication is
каких-то позиций А мило общение это
simple Well hello How are you What are
просто Ну здравствуйте Как дела Чем
you doing That is, about nothing Yes you are just interested Do you have
тебя просто интересно у тебя ко мне есть
any question for me as an
какой-то вопрос как к
American Yes no I’m happy for
Американ Да нет рад за
you I’ll move
вас по иду
on Just
дальше Просто
Yas like squeak  comment letter to my
Ясь лайк писка комент пись на мий
Telegram directly at once axis VN
Telegram прямо зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube taking
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the skarg ODS in your ban and even more
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
richly  I don’t show videos to people at all times, I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for this purpose, so that the
показуе информация про стримы тому для
Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
is written directly at once, and Popik is there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim video, shchezh Tsikava and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
Korisna information and we are guilty of you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
trimati postiyny operational link,
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
regardless of that, show you about  tse
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава украини пись
with
с